const e="englishlit",a=200,o=75,t=[{id:75,question:"To whom does her in line 5 refers to?  ",option:{a:"God  ",b:"Letter  ",c:"World ",d:"Nature"},section:`This is my letter to the world
That never wrote to me
The simple news nature told
With tender majesty
Her message is committed
To hands, I cannot see;
For love of her, set countrymen,
Judge tenderly one me.
`,image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:76,question:"The suddenly her heart was whipped up, she now rode on strange waves: alone defying the wind and the rain; alone, fighting hunger and thirst in the desert, alone, struggling with strange demons in the forest bringing  glad tidings to her people. The mood of the lady in this  passage is one of ",option:{a:"simple defiance ",b:"defeat  ",c:"triumphant  ",d:"depression"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:77,question:"Mother, didn’t you hear me? I’ve brought the goat, hen and yams. Don’t you want them anymore? Why do you continue to look at me like that? I haven’t done anything wrong, again, have I, answer me, speak to me, mother’  The  dominant mood in this passage is one of ",option:{a:"sadness ",b:"anxiety  ",c:"anger  ",d:"nonchalance."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:78,question:"What distinguishes poetry from other  forms of literature is its  ",option:{a:"Rhyme and verse ",b:"rhythm and metaphor ",c:"emotion and feeling  ",d:"irony and paradox"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:79,question:"Assonance poetry is the repetition of ",option:{a:"internal vowels in words ",b:"consonant sounds in words ",c:"final sounds at the end of a line 1 ",d:"final sounds at the beginning of a line"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:80,question:"There knells a jigger, a louse , a weevil, a flea, a bedbug! He is mistletoe, a parasite that lives on the trees of other people’s! the speaker uses a string of ",option:{a:"metaphors  ",b:"parables  ",c:"hyperboles  ",d:"riddles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:81,question:"As literacy form the short  story is most closely related to ",option:{a:"the discourse ",b:"the novel  ",c:"story telling  ",d:"poetry "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:82,question:"A poem written on a grand theme, in an appropriately grand style, dealing, with heroic figures is called ",option:{a:"an epigram  ",b:"an epic ",c:"a soliloquy ",d:"heroic poem"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:83,question:"The literary device which uses ridicule to correct social ills is known as ",option:{a:"anecdote  ",b:"saturation  ",c:"hyperbole  ",d:"satire."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:84,question:"Characterization is a novel means the ",option:{a:"list of characters featuring in it ",b:"peculiar materialisms of the narrator ",c:"mode of presenting the fictional individuals ",d:"list of those that act the novel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:85,question:"Caricature is used to ",option:{a:"censure an individual by emphasizing his weakness ",b:"expose the folly  in literature  ",c:"ridicule a person by distorting his most prominent features ",d:"elicit the artistic potential of dramatist."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:86,question:"The branch of knowledge that places emphasis on beauty is ",option:{a:"philosophy ",b:"ode to pretty ",c:"philology ",d:"aesthetics."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:87,question:"‘The madman has entered our house with violence  defiling our sacred grounds claiming the single truth of the universe bending down our priest with iron’. Mazzizi Kunnene’s progress the imagery of the line above captures the idea of ",option:{a:"coercion ",b:"truth ",c:"religiosity ",d:"persuasion."},section:`‘You kiss her on the cheek 
You kiss her open-sore lips
As white people do.
You suck slimy saliva
From each other’s moths.
As white people do.
Okot P’ Breck’s song of larie
`,image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:88,question:"‘The madman has entered our house with violence  defiling our sacred grounds claiming the single truth of the universe bending down our priest with iron’. Mazzizi Kunnene’s progress the imagery of the line above captures the idea of ",option:{a:"coercion ",b:"truth ",c:"religiosity ",d:"persuasion."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:89,question:"‘Beholds her, single in the field you solitary Highland Lass! Reaping and singing, by herself stop here, or gently pass! Alone she cuts and blinds the gram, and sings a melancholy strain, O listen! For the Vale profound Is overflowing with the sound. The rhyming schema in the first stanza of The Solitary Reaper above is ",option:{a:"abcbddee ",b:"ababccdd ",c:"alxabcdd ",d:"abcbddef"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:90,question:"The tone of the poet is ",option:{a:"optimistic ",b:"dupplicatory  ",c:"sympathetic ",d:"piteous"},section:`These only tears
Dripping down the tears on your depressed face.
Will one day be staunche.
I swear’ 
`,image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:91,question:"The literary device  which anticipates that an event will take place is best described as ",option:{a:"parody ",b:"flashback ",c:"foreshadowing ",d:"rising action "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:92,question:"The multiple deaths in the play serve as a punishment for ",option:{a:"impatience on the part of  Romeo and Juliet; ",b:"imposing life partners on children ",c:"disobedience of the protagonists  ",d:"Tybalt’s fiery temper."},section:"Question is based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:93,question:"Romeo’s death becomes inevitable because ",option:{a:"Emire Lawrence’s is not delivered: ",b:"Juliet is married to Paris ",c:"Romeo kills Tybalt in a duel ",d:"Juliet has committed suicide."},section:"Question is based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:94,question:"Before he met Juliet, Romeo was in love with ",option:{a:"country Paris ",b:"Rosaline  ",c:"Benvolio  ",d:"Mercuito"},section:"Question is based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:95,question:"The major reason for Juliet’s  grief is ",option:{a:"The death of her cousin; ",b:"her reluctant marriage to Romeo  ",c:"the banishment of her lover ",d:"her imminent death."},section:"Question is based on William Shakespeare’s Romeo and Juliet",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:96,question:"Winston Smith begins his rebellion against the power of the state by ",option:{a:"educating the youth  ",b:"keeping a private diary  ",c:"purchasing arms ",d:"disobeying Big Brother."},section:"Question is based on George Orwell’s Nineteen Eighty-four",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:97,question:"In the novel, Orwell attempts  to ",option:{a:"eulogizes the beauty of the socialist system; ",b:"condemn the disgusting hypocrisy of all communist systems; ",c:"satirize the artificiality  of a machine controlled society ",d:"deride the political lock jam in Nigeria."},section:"Question is based on George Orwell’s Nineteen Eighty-four",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:98,question:"“The experts, of course disagree the urine test they ordered ‘said, Negative’. The lives above from acqah’s in the Nanel of the soul depict ",option:{a:"awareness ",b:"inevitability ",c:"progress ",d:"contradiction."},section:"Question is based on selected poems",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:99,question:"In Kunene’s Heritage of Liberation, freedom is to be achieved through the efforts of ",option:{a:"the new generation  ",b:"the old generation ",c:"present generation ",d:"successive generations."},section:"Question is based on selected poems",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:312,question:"In the play, the character of Lawyer B is represented through the use of",option:{a:"flashback",b:"dialogue",c:"play-within-the-play",d:"irony"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:313,question:"James Ofosu’s desire is to see Maanan trained as",option:{a:"a choreographer",b:"an attorney",c:"an accountant",d:"a surgeon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:314,question:"The plot of the play is,",option:{a:"linear",b:"cyclical",c:"complicated",d:"episodic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:315,question:"What causes the strained relationship between James and Lawyer B?",option:{a:"Betrayal of trust",b:"Standard of education",c:"Working experience",d:"Family differences"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:316,question:"‘Now look what we have: a permanent bloom of ugly paper flowers! The device used by Aaron in the excerpt above is",option:{a:"suspense",b:"rhetorical question",c:"oxymoron",d:"allegory"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:317,question:"When Friar Lawrence asks if the bride is ready, he wants to know if",option:{a:"Juliet is prepared",b:"Rosaline is prepared",c:"the corpse is ready",d:"the bride is dressed"},section:"based on William Shake¬speare’s  	Romeo and Juliet.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:318,question:`‘...So tedious is this day<br>
	As is the night before some festival<br>
	To an impatient child that hath new robes<br>
	And may not wear them.’<br>
What makes Juliet’s night so tedious is the`,option:{a:"murder of Tybalt by Romeo",b:"arranged marriage between her and Paris",c:"Eagerness’ to be married to Romeo",d:"unconsummated marriage with Romeo"},section:"based on William Shake¬speare’s  	Romeo and Juliet.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:319,question:`‘...So tedious is this day<br>
	As is the night before some festival<br>
	To an impatient child that hath new robes<br>
	And may not wear them.’<br>
The literary device used in the excerpt is`,option:{a:"euphemism",b:"simile",c:"sarcasm",d:"bathos"},section:"based on William Shake¬speare’s  	Romeo and Juliet.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:320,question:"The atmosphere of tragedy in the play is created through the use of",option:{a:"dreams and foreboding",b:"fights and quarrels",c:"wars and hatred",d:"ideas and dramatization"},section:"based on William Shake¬speare’s  	Romeo and Juliet.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:321,question:"Shakespeare depicts love and idealism through the",option:{a:"party at tire Capulets’",b:"lovers’ tomb at the end",c:"brawl between Romeo and Tybalt",d:"balcony scene in the second Act."},section:"based on William Shake¬speare’s  	Romeo and Juliet.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:322,question:"In the novel, the party approves separation of couples only",option:{a:"on condition of infidelity",b:"where there are no children",c:"in situation of irreconcilable differences",d:"on the death of one of the couples"},section:"based on George Orwell’s  	Nineteen Eighty-Four",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:323,question:"One of the themes of the novel is",option:{a:"colonialism",b:"repression",c:"senility",d:"destruction"},section:"based on George Orwell’s  	Nineteen Eighty-Four",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:324,question:"Newspeak, the official language of Oceania, is devised to",option:{a:"meet the ideological needs of Ingsoc",b:"help devoted party men and women",c:"provide a medium of expression for world-view only",d:"assist by cutting the choice of words for party members."},section:"based on George Orwell’s  	Nineteen Eighty-Four",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:325,question:"The main concern of Winston in the novel is to",option:{a:"take power for himself",b:"acquire wealth",c:"overthrow the party",d:"bring social change"},section:"based on George Orwell’s  	Nineteen Eighty-Four",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:326,question:"“We are hereto die of raget !say die of rage because this time the uncircumcised have gone too far...” The word uncircumcised in the statement above by Nli refers to",option:{a:"Nua and Mvondo",b:"the whites",c:"the people of Doum",d:"the white farmers."},section:"based on Ferdinand Oyono’s,  	The Old Man and the Medal.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:327,question:"The only two sons of Meka die fighting for",option:{a:"independence",b:"the colonialists",c:"the church",d:"the in people."},section:"based on Ferdinand Oyono’s,  	The Old Man and the Medal.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:328,question:"In the novel; Africanness is .achieved in both",option:{a:"setting and characterization",b:"narration and style",c:"diction and syntax",d:"pun and style"},section:"based on Ferdinand Oyono’s,  	The Old Man and the Medal.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:329,question:"What prompts Nnu Ego to run to the effigy of her chi is that ...",option:{a:"she is worried and sick",b:"she is pregnant",c:"the chi asks her to come",d:"milk is dripping from her breasts."},section:"based on Buchi Emecheta’s  	The Joys of Motherhood",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:330,question:"In the society of Nwokocha Agbadi, a man’s social rating determined by his",option:{a:"oratorical power",b:"physical prowess",c:"gentle men",d:"altruistic actions"},section:"based on Buchi Emecheta’s  	The Joys of Motherhood",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:331,question:"‘look at me jubilant for being given another opportunity to 	live longer, and see this foolish woman eager to end her own life when her Maker is not yet ready for her...’The opportunity referred to in the extract above is",option:{a:"the misunderstanding between Nnaife and his wife",b:"narrowly escaping being knocked down",c:"the driver’s encounter with Nnu Ego",d:"ominous visit of Agunwa"},section:"based on Buchi Emecheta’s  	The Joys of Motherhood",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:332,question:"Thorn in “Adeoti’sNaked Soles” symbolizes",option:{a:"victory",b:"bleakness",c:"destruction",d:"suffering"},section:"based on selected poems from Ker, D. et al (eds.) New poetry from Africa; Soyinka W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa: Senanu, K E and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African poetry; Umukoro, M et al (eels.): Exam Focus: Lit-erature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination guides; Nwoga, D.I (ed.): West African Verse andAdeoti G: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:333,question:"‘Pregnant clouds Ride Safely on its back’ Pregnant clouds in Rubadiri’s “An AfricanThunderstorm implies”",option:{a:"uncertainty",b:"calmness",c:"disbelief",d:"fertility"},section:"based on selected poems from Ker, D. et al (eds.) New poetry from Africa; Soyinka W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa: Senanu, K E and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African poetry; Umukoro, M et al (eels.): Exam Focus: Lit-erature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination guides; Nwoga, D.I (ed.): West African Verse andAdeoti G: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:334,question:"The phrase the sunset in Kunene’s “A Heritage of Liberation” refers to",option:{a:"critical need",b:"old age",c:"patience",d:"caution"},section:"based on selected poems from Ker, D. et al (eds.) New poetry from Africa; Soyinka W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa: Senanu, K E and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African poetry; Umukoro, M et al (eels.): Exam Focus: Lit-erature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination guides; Nwoga, D.I (ed.): West African Verse andAdeoti G: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:335,question:"‘The silence of the battlefield heralds the widow’s anguish’ The widow in the lines above in Launko’s “Endof the War” is in anguish because of the",option:{a:"confirmation of her husband’s death",b:"uncertainty over her husband returning alive",c:"delay in the husband’s return from the battlefield",d:"death of all the soldiers in the battlefield"},section:"based on selected poems from Ker, D. et al (eds.) New poetry from Africa; Soyinka W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa: Senanu, K E and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African poetry; Umukoro, M et al (eels.): Exam Focus: Lit-erature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination guides; Nwoga, D.I (ed.): West African Verse andAdeoti G: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:336,question:"The end of “Give Me The Minstrel’s Seat”, seems to suggest that one needs the",option:{a:"support of others",b:"complete command of one’s wives",c:"support of one’s kinsmen",d:"aid of poets"},section:"based on selected poems from Ker, D. et al (eds.) New poetry from Africa; Soyinka W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa: Senanu, K E and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African poetry; Umukoro, M et al (eels.): Exam Focus: Lit-erature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination guides; Nwoga, D.I (ed.): West African Verse andAdeoti G: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:337,question:"According to “Give Me The Minstrels Seat”, a woman is",option:{a:"a necessary evil",b:"only fulfilled when married",c:"naturally jealous",d:"a harbinger of good luck"},section:"based on selected poems from Ker, D. et al (eds.) New poetry from Africa; Soyinka W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa: Senanu, K E and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African poetry; Umukoro, M et al (eels.): Exam Focus: Lit¬erature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination guides; Nwoga, D.I (ed.): West African Verse andAdeoti G: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:338,question:"In Marvel’s “To His Coy Mistress”, the poet-persona tries to",option:{a:"Build up the climax of expectation of women",b:"discuss how a woman labour hard",c:"meet the people’s expectation in a religious adventure",d:"discuss the nature of man and the value of time."},section:"based on selected poems from Ker, D. et al (eds.) New poetry from Africa; Soyinka W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa: Senanu, K E and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African poetry; Umukoro, M et al (eels.): Exam Focus: Lit¬erature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination guides; Nwoga, D.I (ed.): West African Verse andAdeoti G: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:339,question:"In Lawrence’s Bat, the poet’s attitude to bat is one of",option:{a:"fear",b:"sarcasm",c:"contempt",d:"flattering"},section:"based on selected poems from Ker, D. et al (eds.) New poetry from Africa; Soyinka W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa: Senanu, K E and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African poetry; Umukoro, M et al (eels.): Exam Focus: Lit¬erature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination guides; Nwoga, D.I (ed.): West African Verse andAdeoti G: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:340,question:"The first stariza of Eliot’s “The Journey of the Magi” depict the",option:{a:"hazards of the journey",b:"increment of fortune for the pilgrims",c:"blind acceptance of faith",d:"journey as an influential factor."},section:"based on selected poems from Ker, D. et al (eds.) New poetry from Africa; Soyinka W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa: Senanu, K E and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African poetry; Umukoro, M et al (eels.): Exam Focus: Lit¬erature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination guides; Nwoga, D.I (ed.): West African Verse andAdeoti G: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:341,question:"In cope’s “Sonnet VII”, poets are presented; as",option:{a:"recluses",b:"travelers",c:"sociologists",d:"searchers"},section:"based on selected poems from Ker, D. et al (eds.) New poetry from Africa; Soyinka W. (ed.): Poems of Black Africa: Senanu, K E and Vincent, T. (eds.): A Selection of African poetry; Umukoro, M et al (eels.): Exam Focus: Lit¬erature in English; Eruvbetine, A. E. et al (eds.): Longman Examination guides; Nwoga, D.I (ed.): West African Verse andAdeoti G: Naked Soles.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:342,question:"A poetic devices in which an idea in a line runs into another is called",option:{a:"rhyme scheme",b:"enjambment",c:"end rhyme",d:"pathos"},section:"based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:343,question:"The use of sound pattern to suggest meaning in poetry is",option:{a:"rhythm",b:"mimics",c:"lyric",d:"metonymy"},section:"based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:344,question:"A conscious imitation of a literary work by another with the aim of ridicule is",option:{a:"mimesis",b:"performance",c:"mockery",d:"parody"},section:"based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:345,question:"The use of gestures to communicate in drama is known as",option:{a:"burlesque",b:"soliloquy",c:"mime",d:"melodrama"},section:"based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:346,question:"A short and witty remark is",option:{a:"a limerick",b:"a tercel",c:"an epigram",d:"a litotes"},section:"based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:347,question:"An expression that signifies a whole through its significant parts is",option:{a:"synesthesia",b:"synecdoche",c:"metonymy",d:"allegory"},section:"based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:348,question:"a structural arrangement of units of composition by which one element of equal importance with another is similarly placed is called",option:{a:"repetition",b:"paradox",c:"refrain",d:"parallelism"},section:"based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:349,question:"The pride that contributes to the fall of a tragic character in a play is known as",option:{a:"hamartia",b:"catharsis",c:"hubris",d:"epistasis"},section:"based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:350,question:"metrical foot of two stressed or long syllables is called",option:{a:"a spondee",b:"a trochee",c:"an anapest",d:"an iamb"},section:"based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:351,question:"A group of three lyric stanzas in classical Greek poetry is referred to as",option:{a:"triplet",b:"triolet",c:"trilogy.",d:"triad"},section:"based on General Literary Principles.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:352,question:`Biokun:  I did it for her! Let them laugh!<br>
				Let them condemn me. I who have always <br>	
				derided superstition. I have gone bach to the <br>
				shrine of Olokun. At least if he dies, Oroki <br>
				will know I tried everything. <br>
				(Femi I Qsofisan: No More the Wasted Breed)<br>
Biokun’s mood in this passage is one of`,option:{a:"desperation",b:"frustration",c:"anger",d:"anxiety"},section:"based on Literary Appreciation",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:353,question:`	‘My song is the root<br>
	touching other roots <br>
	in a covenant below the crust..’<br>
	(Niyi  Osundare: Waiting Laughters)<br>

The imagery used in the second line of the extract above is`,option:{a:"olfactory",b:"visual",c:"tactile",d:"auditory"},section:"based on Literary Appreciation",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:354,question:`‘The huge sacrifice that <br>
	wards off death <br>
	The big offering that <br>
	prevents diseases....’ <br>
	( Temi Osofison: Morountodun ) <br>
The poem above can best be described as`,option:{a:"epic",b:"heroic",c:"praise",d:"quatrain"},section:"based on Literary Appreciation",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:355,question:`Why blame her who denies love for the asking <br><br>
	And not the Birds and Moths and Beetles <br>
	That after deep draughts from rich nectar wells <br>
	Flee the drained petals to virgin flowers. <br>
The lines above are an indictment of`,option:{a:"adultery",b:"gluttony",c:"flirtation",d:"infertility"},section:"based on Literary Appreciation",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:356,question:`	Oh, the market is set like the hub of a wheel <br>
	And it pulfs 	like a magnet strong <br>
	It is easy to tell <br>
	How it casts its spell <br>
	And draws all the crowds along. <br><br>
The sound device used in the extract above is`,option:{a:"rhyme",b:"alliteration",c:"emphasis",d:"assonance"},section:"based on Literary Appreciation",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:357,question:"A reference beyond the immediate purview of what is being presented is known as",option:{a:"allusion",b:"diversion",c:"inversion",d:"imagery"},section:"based on Literary Appreciation",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:358,question:"‘The how is her barber’ The line is an example",option:{a:"metaphor",b:"hyperbole",c:"personification",d:"litotes"},section:"based on Literary Appreciation",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:359,question:`‘From the sky suspended <br>
	the strings of tattered pants <br>
	marched on trembling feet <br>
	under stone heavy-kits <br>
	marched, on their breast <br>
	scared, monogram of skulls and bones.’ <br>
	( Ossie Enejwe: Mass for the Dead ) <br><br>
“The subject matter of the extract above is`,option:{a:"wastage",b:"war",c:"love",d:"hatred"},section:"based on Literary Appreciation",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:360,question:`‘Tonderai was assisted by the villages in placing his truck box into the back for the car and he got into the passenger side of the truck. Initially, he was a bit nervous and clearly uncomfortable, his young mind was asking how someone whom, he had almost caused a serious accident could be his benefactor.’ ( Daniel T. Manyika: Two worlds Apart )

<br><br>The narrative point of view used in the extract above can best be described as`,option:{a:"omniscient",b:"subjective",c:"panoramic",d:"scenic"},section:"based on Literary Appreciation",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:361,question:`‘Me to the Orangery<br> 
	Solitude invites, <br>
	a wagtail, to tell the<br>  			
	tangled-wood-tale.’ <br>
	( Christopher Okigbo: Heavengate ) <br><br>
The complexity of the poem can be ascribed to the poet’s use of`,option:{a:"archaic diction",b:"structural inversion",c:"compound words",d:"extended met"},section:"based on Literary Appreciation",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"}],i={subject:e,status:200,total:75,data:t};export{t as data,i as default,a as status,e as subject,o as total};
